Cuckoo, cuckoo
كو كو، كو كو
What are you standing there for?
وش واقف هنا كذا ليه؟
The bridal sedan chair
الهودج
took Xiu Gu away.
أخذوا شيو غو ومشوا بها.
Impossible.
مستحيل.
Xiu Gu wouldn't go to the Huo family.
شيو غو مستحيل تروح لبيت هوو.
She was taken by force.
أخذوها وهي مربوطة.
Xiu Gu!
شيو غو!
What are you shouting for?
ليش تصرخ كذا؟
Tell that Huo guy to come out!
نادوا اللي اسمه هوو يطلع!
Xiu Gu!
شيو غو!
Fat Uncle.
يا الخال السمين!
What brings you to my door?
جاي لباب بيتي، وش تبي؟
You're like a fly gathering honey,
يا ولد، تسوي نفسك نحلة!
playing dumb, aren't you?
تتظاهر بالجنون!
Where have you hidden Xiu Gu?
وين خبّيت شيو غو؟
Tell her to come out!
نادها تطلع.
Hold on, hold on.
لحظة، لحظة.
I brought Xiu Gu home as my lawfully wedded wife.
شيو غو أنا تزوجتها زواجًا شرعيًا.
Now you're at my door,
وأنت الحين عند باب بيتي،
looking for my wife.
وجاي تدور على الحرمة حقتي،
That's a bit unreasonable, isn't it?
هذا ما ينقال، صح؟
Second floor of the winery.
الطابق الثاني فوق محل الخمر.
What second floor?
أي طابق ثاني؟
You saw it all, didn't you?
أنت شفت بعينك!
Saw what?
شفت إيش؟
I didn't see anything.
ما شفت شي.
Xiu Gu
شيو غو...
would never marry you.
مستحيل تتزوجك.
This man,
هذا الرجال،
he has feelings for Xiu Gu.
قلبه مال لشيو غو.
I can understand that.
أنا أفهمه.
After all, Xiu Gu is a good woman.
بالأخير شيو غو حرمة طيبة.
Otherwise,
وإلا،
I wouldn't have liked her for so long either.
ما كنت أحبها كل هالمدة.
Right?
صح ولا لا؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Everyone knows
الكل يدري،
Xiu Gu is your savior.
شيو غو هي اللي أنقذت حياتك.
How can you harbor
كيف تقدر تجاه منقذة حياتك
covetous thoughts toward your savior?
تطمع فيها كذا؟
Xiu Gu is my childhood betrothed.
شيو غو مخطوبة لي من وهي صغيرة.
Only I can give her a good life.
أنا وحدي أقدر أوفّر لها عيشة طيبة.
You've only been here a few days.
أنت لك كم يوم جاي؟
So I'm warning you.
عشان كذا أحذّرك،
If you keep pestering my Xiu Gu,
لو رجعت تلاحق شيو غو حقتنا،
I won't be polite.
ما راح أجاملك.
This man is unreasonable.
هذا ما يفهم بالعقل.
Tell him to leave.
خلّوه يمشي.
Go, leave.
امشِ، امشِ!
It's very simple.
الموضوع بسيط.
Call Xiu Gu out to say it to my face.
نادوا شيو غو، وخلوها تقول قدّامنا.
You're being pestering and unreasonable.
تخبيص وعناد!
See him out.
ودّعوه برا.
Stop right there.
قف مكانك!
What do you want to do?
يا ولد، وش ناوي تسوي؟
Or else?
وإلا...
Or else what will you do?
وإلا وش بتسوي؟
Fists have no eyes.
اليد والرجل ما لها عين!
Stand back.
قف مكانك!
Go.
امشِ!
Back out.
ارجع لورا واطلع!
Back up.
تراجع!
Keep backing up.
تراجع أكثر!
This is bullying!
هذا ظلم زايد!
What is going on here?
وش اللي يصير هنا؟
Nothing, it's nothing.
ما في شي، ما في شي.
My relative, we have a little conflict.
أقاربي بينهم شوية خلاف.
Commander Qin knows about it.
العقيد تشين يدري.
I won't cause trouble for him.
ما أبي أسبب له مشاكل.
That's enough.
خلاص، كفاية.
Bandits raided the prison.
قطاع طرق هاجموا السجن.
Commander Qin is furious right now.
العقيد تشين معصّب الحين.
Don't cause extra trouble here.
فلا تزيدها مشاكل هنا.
Understood.
مفهوم.
Break it up, break it up.
تفرّقوا، تفرّقوا.
Break it up, move along.
تفرّقوا، تفرّقوا، تفرّقوا!
If you don't release Xiu Gu,
إذا ما طلّعتوا شيو غو،
I'm not leaving.
أنا ما راح أمشي.
Suit yourself then.
على كيفك.
You just wait here.
اقعد هنا وانتظر.
Let's see if you can fly to the sky
أبي أشوفك بتطلع للسماء
or burrow into the earth.
ولا بتدخل تحت الأرض.
Close the door.
سكّروا الباب!
I'm not leaving!
أنا ما مشيت!
Our Qionglai Town intestine noodles,
شعيرية أمعاء الخنزير في بلدة تشيونغلاي،
outsiders usually don't get to eat them.
الغريب عادة ما يذوقها.
Smells so good.
ريحتها تفتح النفس!
Don't talk while eating noodles.
كل الشعيرية ولا تتكلم،
You might choke to death.
لا تشرق وتموت!
Choking is better than starving.
الموت بالشرقة أهون من الجوع.
I'm not leaving.
أنا ما راح أمشي.
I'll find something to eat later.
بعد شوي أجيب شي آكله.
I'll wait you out.
بخليك تذبل لين تموت!
Cinnamon stimulates the appetite
القرفة تفتح الشهية.
Star anise enhances the fragrance
واليانسون النجمي يزيد الريحة.
The spice is just right
الحرّ والبهار على قدّه.
I'm even hungrier now
أنا جعت أكثر!
You have hot and sour noodles
أنت عندك شعيرية حامضة وحارة،
I have soup to drink
وأنا عندي شوربة أشربها.
Why does it smell so good?
ليش ريحتها طيبة كذا؟
It smells pretty good, huh?
ريحة طيبة شوي!
Let's have a pitch-in meal
نسوي وجبة تشاركية؟
How do we do that?
كيف يعني؟
I'll provide the soup and stove
أنا أطلع الشوربة والموقد،
Your rotten vegetable leaves...
وأنت هات ورق الخضرة التعبان،
...we cook and eat together
ونطبخها سوا ونأكل.
You don't say
لا تقول،
My belly is getting hungry now
بطني الحين جاعت شوي.
Tell you what, I'll be generous
طيب، أنا بكون كريم شوي.
Bring all the leftover veggies to cook
هاتوا بقايا الخضار كلها نطبخها.
Bring the good ones too
حتى الزين منها هاتوه نطبخه.
Cook them all up
هاتوا كله نطبخه!
Come on, come on
يلا، يلا!
Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up
بسرعة، بسرعة، بسرعة!
Hungry
جعت.
We're all hungry
كلنا جعنا.
Deal
تمام.
Brother, what is this?
يا كبير، شنو هذا؟
Beef offal
أحشاء بقر.
Want to buy some?
تشتري شوية ولا؟
I'm not buying, I'm not buying
ما أشتري، ما أشتري.
Then forget it
خلاص، خلّها.
What is that? It smells so good
شنو هذا؟ ريحته طيبة!
How about a pitch-in meal?
شلونك نسوي وجبة تشاركية؟
How do we do a pitch-in meal?
شلون يعني وجبة تشاركية؟
I provide the soup, pot, and stove
أنا أجيب الشوربة والقدر والموقد.
And the tables and benches
وأنا أجيب الطاولة والكراسي.
You just provide the beef offal
إنت بس تجيب أحشاء البقر.
We eat together
ونأكل سوا.
Sure
تمام.
My belly is hungry anyway
على كل حال بطني جوعانة.
Come on, come on
تعالوا، تعالوا.
Let's eat meat!
يلا ناكل لحم!
The soup is fragrant, no tummy trouble
ريحة القدر طالعة، لا تسوي نفسك شجاع.
I'll provide the loach
أنا أجيب لوتش.
Herbs are nourishing, just missing tripe
الأعشاب مقوية، ناقصنا بس الكرشة.
I'll provide the tripe
أنا أجيب الكرشة.
Chicken, duck, fish, meat, anything goes
دجاج وبط وسمك ولحم، كله يمشي.
Anything goes
كله يمشي.
Radish, blood curd, and tofu
فجل ودم متخثّر مع توفو.
Eat tofu, eat tofu
كلوا التوفو، كلوا التوفو.
Pitch-in meal, sit in a circle
وجبة تشاركية، نقعد حلقة.
Contribute more...
اللي يدفع أكثر،
...eat more
ياكل أكثر.
Contribute less...
واللي يدفع أقل،
...still get full
برضه يشبع.
Contribute nothing, sit comfortably too
وحتى اللي ما يطلع شي، قعدته مريحة.
That's right
صحيح.
Come on, come on
تعالوا، تعالوا.
Cook it up, cook it up
غمّسوا، غمّسوا!
Who are you looking for?
تدورون على مين؟
Come, come
تعال، تعال.
Come here
تعال هنا.
Sit
اقعد.
Is your Young Mistress in?
الست الصغيرة عندكم موجودة؟
Who are you?
إنت مين؟
None of your business who I am
وش دخّلك أنا مين؟
I'm just looking for your Young Mistress
أنا جاي أدور على ستّكم الصغيرة.
Our Eldest Young Master hasn't been gone long
سيدنا الكبير توّه رايح من شوي.
And you dare hit on our Young Mistress?
وتجرؤ تفكّر بستّنا الصغيرة؟
Qin Dahan... Qin...
تشين داهان، تشين!
What are you talking about?
شنو اللي تهذر به؟
I'm here to deliver something
أنا جاي أوصل شي.
A jar of Qiong wine
جرة من خمر تشيونغ.
Here, take it, take it
تفضل، خذها، خذها.
There's this chubby guy
فيه ولد سمين،
Told me to give this letter to your Young Mistress
قال لي أسلّم هالرسالة لستّكم الصغيرة.
I opened it and took a look
فتحتها ونظرت فيها شوي.
But I didn't understand it
وبرضه ما فهمت.
He repeatedly warned me...
ووصّاني مرارًا،
...not to give it to your Old Master
لا أسلّمها لشيخكم الكبير.
You don't look like the Old Master anyway
وإنت من شكلك مو الشيخ الكبير.
Take it
خذها.
Stool... Snail... Sound...
دِنغ، وُو، شيانغ.
Young Mistress
يا ستّنا الصغيرة.
Eldest Young Master
يا سيدنا الكبير.
Where is that chubby guy now?
وين الولد السمين الحين؟
You mean the chubby guy?
تقصد الولد السمين؟
Where is the chubby guy...
وين الولد السمين؟
I'm asking you!
أنا أسألك إنت!
Don't rush, don't rush, let me think
لا تخاف، لا تخاف، خلّني أفكّر.
I remember now
تذكّرت.
Where?
وينه؟
I came out to buy meat
طلعت أشتري لحم.
I paid the money
دفعت الفلوس.
He hasn't given me the meat yet!
بس هو لسه ما سلّمني اللحم.
I haven't finished talking, why run?
لسه ما تكلمت، ليش تهرب؟
Since you're already here...
ما دمتَ جيت،
Stay for lunch before you go.
كُل الغدا وبعدين امشِ.
Forget it.
خلّها.
About this marriage...
تقول هالزواجة هذي،
I really don't understand it.
والله ما عاد أفهمها أبدًا.
Before the wedding,
قبل ما تدخل بيتهم،
everything was exactly as it should be.
كل اللي لازم كان موجود، ما نقص شي.
But after she crossed the threshold,
وبعد ما دخلت بيتهم،
I'm the Huo family's father-in-law, aren't I?
أنا حما عائلة هوو، مو كذا؟
How did things end up like this?
شلون صارت السالفة بهالشكل؟
It's been days now.
صار لها كم يوم.
I haven't stepped away from here once.
وأنا هنا ما تحرّكت خطوة.
Xiu Gu has never come out.
شيو غو ما طلعت ولا مرة.
Whether she's doing well or not in there,
وش وضعها بالداخل، زين ولا شين،
nobody knows.
ما ندري.
Why wouldn't she be doing well?
شلون يعني تكون بخير؟
My son-in-law has always treated her fine.
زوج بنتي دايمًا معاملته لها طيبة.
They grew up together.
هذولا اثنين تربّوا سوا من الصغر.
Young Master Huo has been sensible since childhood.
السيد الشاب هوو عاقل من وهو صغير.
I don't think it's come to that.
ما أظن توصل لهالحد.
I don't want to talk to you about this.
ما أبي أتكلم معك بهالكلام.
When I rescue Xiu Gu later,
لما نطلع شيو غو من هناك،
I'll have her tell you herself.
خلّها هي تشرح لك بنفسها.
Rescue?
نطلعها؟
Why would you need to "rescue" her?
شلون تقولون “نطلعها” أصلًا؟
Come out, come out, let Xiugu come out!
اخرجوا، اخرجوا، أخرجوا شيوغو!
What is going on here?
وش السالفة هذي؟
These people are here for a pitch-in meal with me.
هذولا جايين يسوّون معي وجبة تشاركية،
We're having hotpot.
عشان ياكلون قدر حار.
They brought their own meat and vegetables.
هم يجيبون اللحم والخضار من عندهم،
Some even brought me wine.
وفيه اللي جاب لي شراب بعد.
Come out, come out, let Xiugu come out!
اخرجوا، اخرجوا، أخرجوا شيوغو!
Since I'm stuck waiting here anyway,
أنا بقعد هنا وأطوّلها.
anyone who wants to join the pitch-in meal
اللي يبي وجبة تشاركية،
has to shout this slogan.
لازم يهتف بهالشعار.
Come out, come out, let Xiugu come out!
اخرجوا، اخرجوا، أخرجوا شيوغو!
A beggar from out of town
شحاد غريب عن الديرة،
dares to come to our Huo family turf
يتجرأ على أرض عائلة هوو،
and shame the Huo family name?
ويفضحنا قدّام الناس!
Is he some giant snake we can't pin down?
ثعبان أسود طويل، ما ينكتم!
When he's done making a scene,
خلّوه لين يشبع صياح.
we'll just spend a little money
بالأخير ندفع كم قرش،
and have Commander Qin charge him with disturbing the peace.
ونخلي العقيد تشين يلفّق له تهمة إثارة شغب.
Let him learn that
عشان يعرف
our Young Master is red-hot iron—
إن سيدنا مثل الحديد المحمّى،
you can't even touch him.
ما ينلمس حتى.
That hits the spot!
ولا يقدر يقرب له أبدًا.
Let him make a scene.
خلّوه يهوّش،
It's ready!
كفاية.
Come on in for the pitch-in meal!
ادخلوا، تقدرون تسوّون وجبة تشاركية.
Come on, come on!
يلا يلا يلا.
You're really something.
أنت طلعت قدّها.
With the crowd you draw,
بهالشعبية اللي عندك،
if you turned this into a business,
لو سوّيناها شغل،
you'd make a fortune.
بنغتني منها.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Boss Dong,
يا معلم دونغ،
this might be more profitable than selling wine!
هذي يمكن تربح أكثر من بيع الشراب.
Right, right, right.
إي إي إي.
If you take your wine
هات شرابك
and sell it here,
وبِعه هنا،
you'll definitely make more money.
أكيد أربح لك.
Boss Dong,
يا معلم دونغ،
this shop is yours, right?
المحل هذا لك؟
Why don't you give it a name?
سمّه باسم.
That's right!
إي صح.
Alright, alright.
تمام، تمام.
Look here,
شوفوا يا جماعة،
we've all gathered here
إحنا كلنا عشان الأكل الطيب
for the love of good food.
اجتمعنا هنا.
Let's call it "Gourmet Gathering."
خلّوه “ملتقى المأكولات”.
Gourmet Gathering?
“ملتقى المأكولات”.
Sounds good, sounds good!
تمام، تمام.
Hold on.
لا تستعجلون.
My surname is Dong.
أنا اسمي دونغ.
So let's call it "Dongshihui."
المحل هذا اسمه دونغ شي هوي.
Great, great, great!
تمام، تمام، تمام.
That works, that works!
زين، زين، زين.
Dongshihui! Dongshihui! Dongshihui!
دونغ شي هوي، دونغ شي هوي، دونغ شي هوي!
Let's eat, let's eat!
كلوا كلوا كلوا!
Come on down.
انزلوا!
Hurry!
بسرعة!
Over there.
هناك
What do you mean?
شنو يعني؟
We start from there...
نحنا من هناك
...and dig a tunnel to the Huo house.
نحفر نفق لحد بيت هوو
Dig our way through.
ونحفر لحد عندهم
That's a bit extreme.
مو لهالدرجة!
Do you want to see Xiu Gu or not?
تريد تشوف شيو غو ولا لا؟
Of course.
طبعًا
They won't let us see her.
هم دايمًا ما يخلّونا نشوفها
Don't you think that's strange?
ما تحسّه شي غريب؟
If we don't dig through from here...
إذا ما حفرنا من هنا ووصلنا
...and find Xiu Gu...
ونشوف شيو غو
...how will you know...
شلون بتعرف إنها بالداخل
...if she's safe...
بخير ولا بشر
...or dead or alive?
حيّة ولا ميّتة؟
Just the two of us?
بس إحنا الاثنين
Don't you have a better plan?
ما عندك طريقة أحسن؟
The two of us
إحنا الاثنين
Eat hotpot by day
بالنهار ناكل هوت بوت
Dig holes by night
وبالليل نحفر نفق
Fortune telling! Marriage divination!
نقرأ الطالع ونحسب النصيب
No charge if it's not accurate!
إذا ما طلع صح ما آخذ فلوس!
Miss
يا أختي الكبيرة
Your cheeks are flushed like rosy clouds
خدودك مورّدة مثل الشفق
You're about to get lucky in love
واضح إن حظّك بالحب جاي
Let me read your fortune
خلّيني أحسب لك شوي
You creep
يا قليل الأدب
Don't go
لا تروح
That hotpot place is interesting
مطعم الهوت بوت ذاك فيه شي مميّز
The shop is a dump, but the taste is amazing
المكان تعبان بس الطعم يجنّن
Indeed
صحيح
I heard that chubby boss
سمعت إن صاحب المطعم السمين
Made a weird rule
حاطّ قانون غريب بعد
Whoever shouts "Come out, come out"
أي واحد يصرخ: اخرجوا، اخرجوا
Gets a twenty percent discount
يعطونه خصم 20%
Is the boss's surname Sha?
ذاك صاحب المطعم لقبه “الأهبل”
Who has the surname Sha?
من وين يجي لقب “الأهبل”؟
It's because he charges so little
لأنه دايمًا يبيع برخص
He doesn't make any money at all
وما يربح ولا شي
And he looks short and dumpy
وشكله كئيب وقصير
So people call him Boss Sha behind his back
عشان كذا ينادونه وراه “المدير الأهبل”
Then why open a hotpot place if not to make money?
إذا ما يربح، ليش فاتح مطعم؟
Who knows?
من يدري؟
Maybe he has his own plans
يمكن عنده حسابات ثانية
Excuse me
لو سمحت
Where is this hotpot place you mentioned?
وين مطعم الهوت بوت اللي قلتوا عنه؟
Up ahead. Dongshihui
قدّام، دونغ شي هوي
We really want to take you as our master
نحنا جدّيين، نبيك تصير أستاذنا
I just run this hotpot place for fun
أنا فاتح الهوت بوت للتسلية بس
I'm not taking apprentices. No, no
ما أقبل، ما أقبل
Not bad at all
شغلك مضبوط
When did you get here?
من زمان جيت؟
You're everywhere
أنت بكل مكان!
I divined where you were
أنا أعرف وينك من حسابي
Just accept us
يلا اقبلنا تلاميذ عندك
We sincerely want to learn your craft
جايين نتعلّم مهنتك بصدق
This lousy hotpot
هالهوت بوت التعبان
Doesn't require any craft
وين فيه مهارة أصلًا؟
I can't learn anything too difficult either
الشي الصعب ما أقدر أتعلّمه
We just want a skill to make a living
أبي حرفة أسترزق منها وآكل لقمة
Well
هذا...
It's not impossible
مو مستحيل
Alright, alright
طيب، طيب
This hotpot looks simple
الهوت بوت شكله بسيط
But if you want to make it
بس إذا تبي تسويه
Numbing, spicy, fresh, fragrant, and not drying
حار ولذيذ ومعطّر بدون ما يلهب
That is very hard
فهذا صعب
The secret recipe inside
الخلطة السرّية اللي فيه
Isn't something you can figure out quickly
مو بتفهمونها بسرعة
There is no secret recipe
ما فيه سرّ كبير
Just added some herbs
بس نضيف شوية أعشاب طبية
Not worth much
ما تسوى شي
Right, not worth much
إي، ما تسوى شي
But why is it that you
بس ليش أنتم
Can't recreate this flavor?
ما تقدرون تطلعون هالطعم؟
Chinese medicine has a hundred flavors; the difficulty is in the balance
الأعشاب نكهاتها كثيرة، الصعب توازنها
The ins and outs of this
وفيها أسرار وتفاصيل
Are profound. There's plenty for you to learn
علمها كثير، يكفيكم تتعلّمون
Hurry up and call him Master
يلا قولوا: يا أستاذ
Master
يا أستاذ
That's right
كذا صح
It's almost mealtime
قرب وقت الأكل
Go inside and find something to do
ادخلوا ودبّروا لكم شغل
Go in, go in
ادخلوا، ادخلوا
Okay
تمام
You with the yellow teeth, faking expertise
أسنانك مصفرّة وتسوّي نفسك خبير
Coming here to cause trouble?
أول ما جيت صرت تخربط
I'm helping you
أنا قاعد أساعدك
Don't you think this is a business opportunity?
ما تشوفها فرصة تجارة؟
Well
يعني...
Think about it
فكّر فيها
Once you teach the apprentices
تعلّم التلميذ
You can open branches
ويفتح فرع
Apprentices teach more apprentices
والتلميذ يعلّم تلميذ
And open more branches
ويفتح فرع ثاني
When branches are blossoming everywhere
ولما تصير الفروع بكل مكان
You'll be the Grandmaster
تصير أنت شيخ المهنة
As the Grandmaster
وأنت شيخ المهنة
You'll just lie at home counting money every day
كل يوم تتمدّد بالبيت وتعدّ الفلوس
Who is this distinguished expert?
من هذا الخبير العظيم؟
I am Xuanjizi
أنا شوان جي زي
Well said
كلامك مضبوط
I thought only hotpot could make money
كنت أحسب بس الهوت بوت يجيب فلوس
After hearing you say that
بعد كلامك
My vision was a bit narrow
طلع صدري ضيّق شوي
Not at all, not at all
لا لا
I don't want to be any Grandmaster
ما أبي أصير شيخ مهنة
Nor do I want to make money
ولا أبي أربح فلوس
Don't talk nonsense
لا تهرج كذا
Money is a good thing
الفلوس شي زين
Exactly
إي
If not for money, what are you doing this for?
إذا ما تبي تربح، ليش فاتح؟
I'm doing it to
أنا عشان
Take down the bully across the street
أطيّح بالبلطجي اللي قدّامنا
Bully?
بلطجي؟
Over there
هناك
That's a pretty lofty ambition.
طموحك كبير بصراحة
But you're running on nothing but passion.
بس عندك حماس وبس
You've got no bullets.
وما عندك ذخيرة
How can you fight?
شلون بتقاتل؟
Exactly, exactly.
بالضبط، بالضبط
Money is what gives you a backbone.
الفلوس تعطيك سند
We can do both.
والاثنين ما يتعارضون
Right, right.
صحيح، صحيح
Let's do it together.
نحنا سوا، سوا
Together, together.
سوا، سوا
Open a branch, open a branch.
نفتح فرع، نفتح فرع
We can open a branch.
إي نقدر نفتح فرع
The bully is right across the street.
اللي قدّامنا هو البلطجي
Help me dig into their lair.
ساعدوني نحفر لحد وكرهم
Then I'll have time to teach apprentices.
وساعتها يصير عندي وقت أعلّم تلاميذ
That's the only way to fulfill...
وبكذا نحقّق لكم أنتم الاثنين
...your dream of making easy money.
حلم الربح وأنتم متمدّدين
No problem, no problem.
سهلة، سهلة
Together.
سوا
We're all in this together.
كلّنا سوا
Did we dig in the wrong direction?
مو يمكن غلطنا بالاتجاه؟
Impossible.
مستحيل نغلط
I know that underneath their house...
أنا أعرف تحت بيتهم
...there is a cellar for tea...
فيه مخزن للشاي
...and a tunnel to escape disaster.
ونفق لتفادي المصايب
We just need to dig through to their tunnel...
بس إذا وصلنا لنفق بيتهم بالحفر
...and we'll be through.
خلاص نكون وصلنا
Even if they have a tunnel,
حتى لو عندهم نفق
the tunnel should be under the courtyard.
النفق المفروض يكون تحت الدار الكبيرة
Their courtyard should be in that direction.
دارهم الكبيرة المفروض بهالجهة
Impossible.
مستحيل
I think it's right here.
أنا أشوفها من هالناحية
Is your guess even accurate?
تقديرك مضبوط ولا لا؟
Or is my compass more accurate?
ولا بوصلة أنا أدق؟
If we dig wrong, it's all for nothing.
إذا حفرنا غلط، تعبنا يروح هدر
Trust me.
ثق فيّ
This is my trade.
أنا آكل عيشي من هالشغلة
You help out too.
ساعدنا شوي
I provide the brains, you provide the brawn.
أنا أفكّر، وإنت تبذل الجهد
Fair and square.
عدل ومنطقي
You...
إنت!
What's the situation up ahead?
وش السالفة قدّام؟
Queuing for hotpot.
طابور عشان ياكلون هوت بوت
Hotpot?
هوت بوت؟
Hotpot is so unrefined.
هوت بوت هالشي ما له هيبة
What's so good about it?
وش فيه يعني يستاهل؟
I find it strange too.
حتى أنا مستغرب
But there are so many people eating there every day.
كل يوم اللي يروحون ياكلون كثيرين
I'll clear the place immediately.
بفضّي المكان حالًا
Clear out, clear out, clear out!
تفرّقوا، تفرّقوا، تفرّقوا
Go, go, go!
امشوا، امشوا، امشوا
Dongshihui.
دونغ شي هوي
Stop.
قف
Two days ago, this Young Master Huo sent gifts.
قبل يومين السيد الشاب هوو جا وقدّم هدية
Asking me to arrest the boss of Dongshihui.
وقال لي أقبض على صاحب دونغ شي هوي
It seems this Dongshihui boss...
يبدو إن صاحب دونغ شي هوي
...is quite something.
وراه سالفة
Move it, move it.
يلا، يلا
Move it.
يلا
Where is everyone?
وين الناس؟
Why is it all...
ليش كلهم...
A distinguished guest has arrived.
عندنا ضيف عزيز شرّفنا
Clear the tables.
لمّوا الطاولات
Please sit.
تفضّلوا بالجلوس
Please, please.
تفضّلوا، تفضّلوا
Sit, sit, sit.
اقعدوا، اقعدوا، اقعدوا
A tiny hotpot shop.
محل هوت بوت صغير
Looks pretty ordinary to me.
أشوفه عادي جدًا
What signature dishes do you have?
وش عندكم أطباق مميّزة؟
Our shop...
محلّنا
Every dish is a signature dish.
كل طبق عندنا هو طبقنا المميّز
A toad yawning...
ضفدع أقرع يتثاءب
What big talk.
يا لك من متبجّح!
Then bring a bit of everything.
أجل، هاتوا من كل شي شوي
Alright!
أبشر
A bit of every specialty in the house!
هاتوا من أطباقنا المميّزة كلّها شوي
Go personally.
روح بنفسك
Commander Qin.
العقيد تشين
Your distinguished presence...
شرّفتنا بقدومك
Why didn't you tell me?
ليش ما قلت لي من قبل؟
I just stopped by for a hotpot.
مريت آكل هوت بوت بالطريق
No need to disturb Young Master Huo.
ما له داعي نزعج السيد الشاب هوو
This kind of fly-infested joint...
هالمطعم الحقير
Surely can't catch Commander Qin's eye.
يمكن ما يعجب العقيد تشين
I invite Commander Qin...
أدعو العقيد تشين
...to my home for a sit-down.
يتفضّل لبيتي ويقعد شوي
I'll have my chef prepare a good meal for Commander Qin.
وأخلّي طباخ البيت يجهّز لك وليمة محترمة
Flies or mosquitoes, it's all meat.
حتى الذباب والبعوض لحم
I came here for its reputation.
أنا جاي على السمعة
Here it comes!
جايين
Dongshihui's authentic spicy hotpot!
هوت بوت دونغ شي هوي الأصيل الحارّ
What are you doing here?
إنت جاي ليش؟
We don't welcome you here.
إحنا ما نرحّب فيك هنا
Come out, come out, let Xiugu come out!
اخرجوا، اخرجوا، أخرجوا شيوغو!
Commander Qin.
العقيد تشين
This is the scoundrel I told you about.
هذا هو الزعران اللي قلت لك عنه
To steal my woman...
يبغى يخطف حرمتي
He opened this fly-infested joint right at my doorstep.
وفتح هالمطعم الحقير قدّام باب بيتي
Spying on me every day.
يراقبني كل يوم
Just look.
شفت؟
Giving my household no peace.
خلّى بيتي ما فيه راحة لا لدجاج ولا لكلاب
I request Commander Qin...
أطلب من العقيد تشين
...to purge this peace-disturbing...
تطهير البلدة من هالمخرّب للأمن
...lawless element.
المجرم الخارج عن القانون
Commander Qin...
يا عقيد تشين
The parent official of the local people.
أنت راعي أهل البلدة
A good official!
مسؤول طيب
I want to report a crime too.
وأنا بعد ببلّغ للسلطة
This man kidnapped a decent woman.
هذا خطف امرأة شريفة
That is the wife I married with a grand sedan chair.
هذي زوجتي اللي جبتها بموكب عرس كبير
You can't have her, so you slander me here.
لأنك ما قدرت عليها، جاي تتّهمني زور
Ever since she went in...
من يوم دخلت عنده
No sign of her, alive or dead.
لا نشوفها حيّة ولا نلقى لها جثة
Call her out.
نادِها تطلع
Let's confront her face-to-face.
ونواجه بعض وجهًا لوجه
Right.
صح
I came to eat hotpot.
أنا جاي آكل هوت بوت
You're making such a racket.
وإنتوا عاملين دوشة ليش؟
Whatever it is, sit down and talk.
أي شي قولوه وأنتم قاعدين
Sit.
اقعدوا
Fine, sit.
طيب، نقعد
Come, come, come.
يلا، يلا
Talk while we eat.
نتكلم وإحنا ناكل
This hotpot tastes really good.
طعم الهوت بوت هذا فعلًا ممتاز
I think your business is going to get bigger and bigger.
أشوف تجارتك بتكبر يومًا بعد يوم
Once the business gets big,
إذا كبرت التجارة
do you need this officer to do anything for you?
تحتاجني أسوي لك شي ولا لا؟
Yes, yes.
نحتاج، نحتاج
Tell that bastard to release Xiu Gu.
خلّه يطلق شيو غو يا ابن الكلب
Xiu Gu?
شيو غو
Xiu Gu is our young mistress.
شيو غو هي ستّنا الصغيرة في البيت
Is her name something you can just shout out?
اسمها مو لك تناديه على كيفك
Right.
صح
We are all men who do big things.
كلّنا ناس نشتغل بالكبير
Why get so caught up in romance?
ما فيه وقت لهالحبّ والهيام
Commander Qin.
العقيد تشين
This shop was opened for Xiu Gu.
هالمحل انفتح عشان شيو غو
If Xiu Gu isn't here,
إذا شيو غو مو هنا
this shop has no meaning at all.
فالمحل ما له أي معنى
So you mean...
يعني قصدك
Xiu Gu is your shop's treasure?
شيو غو هي كنز محلك
Then just give Xiu Gu back to them.
أجل رجّع شيو غو لأهلها
You can just marry another one.
وتزوّج وحدة ثانية
Marry three, I'll be the matchmaker.
تزوّج ثلاثة، وأنا أخطب لك
Commander Qin.
العقيد تشين
You're making things difficult for me.
كذا إنت تحرجني
Otherwise, what did you think?
وإلا وش كنت تظن؟
What's going on? Don't wreck the place.
وش فيك؟ لا تخرّبونه
Easy, easy, easy.
بالراحة، بالراحة، بالراحة
What?
وش؟
We are...
إحنا هذا...
Reno... renovating.
تج... تجديد
Commander Qin.
العقيد تشين
Renovations are loud, might spoil your appetite a bit.
التجديد صوته عالي، يمكن يقرفك شوي
How about this?
خلّها كذا
I'll pack it up and deliver it to your door later.
بعد شوي أجهّزها لك وأرسلها لبيتك
What is "packing it up"?
وش يعني أجهّزها؟
"Packing it up" means...
يعني أجهّزها هو
pot, stove, and all the dishes,
بالقدر والموقد، وكل الأطباق
all packed up and delivered to your residence.
كلها تتجهّز وتوصل لدارك
This meal is my tribute to Commander Qin.
هالوجبة إكرام مني للعقيد تشين
Sensible.
فاهم الأصول
You should be sensible too.
وإنت بعد لازم تفهم الأصول
I have high hopes for you.
أنا شايف فيك خير
Farewell, Commander Qin.
نودّع العقيد تشين بكل احترام
Up!
انهضوا
She's truly a dwarf crossing a river—dead set on it.
هي مثل القصير يعبر النهر، مطمّنة على الآخر
She hasn't eaten or drunk anything for days.
كل يوم لا تاكل ولا تشرب
She fainted several times in between.
وبالنص أغمي عليها كم مرة
I told Mama Zhang to forcibly...
فناديّت أم تشانغ غصبًا
pour some sugar water down her throat.
تسقيها شوي ميّة سكر
Just to keep her alive.
عشان تظل روحها معلّقة
This can't go on like this.
كذا ما ينفع نستمر
I'm afraid... someone might really die.
أخاف فعلًا تصير مصيبة ويموت أحد
This is the spot.
هنا بالضبط.
The height is right too.
والارتفاع مناسب أيضًا.
Come on, who's doing the final poke?
هيا، من يطعن الطعنة الأخيرة؟
Me, me.
أنا، أنا!
Poked it.
طعنتُها.
Let there be light!
تمّت المباركة.
How come I see the sky?
كيف صرنا نرى السماء؟
I don't see a house.
ولا نرى البيت.
I told you your direction was wrong.
قلت لك إن الاتجاه خطأ!
The compass can't be wrong.
البوصلة لا يمكن أن تخطئ.
This should be the back garden.
هذا المفروض أن يكون الحديقة الخلفية.
Listen, there are birds chirping.
اسمعوا، هناك عصافير تزقزق.
Here, let me go up first.
هيا، أنا أصعد أولًا.
Come, come, come.
تعالوا، تعالوا.
Stand on this.
قف فوقه.
Easy, easy.
على مهلكم، على مهلكم!
Up.
ارفع!
This is a garden, it is a garden.
هنا حديقة، حديقة!
The direction is right.
الاتجاه صحيح، ها؟
Why is there a wall?
كيف ظهرت جدار هنا؟
Garden...
حديقة.
Do you see that?
هل رأيت أم لا؟
Dongshihui.
دونغ شي هوي
The direction was dug correctly,
الاتجاه صحيح في الحفر.
but the distance is way off.
لكن المسافة بعيدة جدًا.
What are you guys doing here?
أنتم، ماذا تفعلون هنا؟
We...
نحن...
Playing hide-and-seek.
نطارد قطًّا.
Caught you.
أمسكتُ بك!
I caught you too.
وأنا أيضًا أمسكتُ بك!
You come catch me.
تعال وامسكني إذن!
Didn't you want Xiu Gu?
ألم تكن تريد شيو غو؟
Bring her over.
أحضروها.
Come.
هيا.
Returning her to you.
ها هي لكم.
Did the Huo family not feed you?
بيت هوو ما كان يطعّمنا.
Don't mention the Huo family ever again.
من الآن لا تذكروا بيت هوو.
I went on a hunger strike myself.
أنا من قررت الإضراب عن الطعام.
I didn't expect that as soon as I got out,
لم أتوقع، ما إن خرجت...
you guys would have opened a hotpot restaurant.
حتى فتحتم مطعم هوت بوت.
And doing so well too.
وطلع شغلكم ممتازًا.
Just look at this hand.
انظر إلى هذه اليد.
Just take a look.
انظر قليلًا.
Look how he tortured you.
كيف عذّبك هكذا؟
That bastard, Huo.
ذاك الوغد، المدعو هوو.
I'm going to settle the score with him.
سأذهب لأحاسبه.
What score can you settle on your own?
وأنت وحدك، ماذا ستحاسبه عليه؟
Xiao Fan
يا شياو فان.
Let's just let this matter go.
دع هذه المسألة تمرّ هكذا.
Young Master Huo caught you then let you go.
السيد الشاب هوو قبض ثم أطلق.
What exactly is his game?
ما معنى هذا بالضبط؟
I can't help but feel...
أشعر دائمًا...
...he's plotting some scheme behind our backs.
أنه يدبّر من وراءنا مكيدة.
We're on the same wavelength.
يشعل الفتيل من الطرفين.
We thought the exact same thing.
فكّرنا بنفس الشيء.
This guy named Huo...
هذا المدعو هوو...
I wonder...
لا أدري إن كان...
The King of Hell's wife is pregnant.
زوجة ملك الجحيم حامل،
What devilish scheme is he brewing?
ماذا يضمر من شر؟
I don't care what devilish scheme he's brewing.
لا يهمني ماذا يضمر من شر.
I'm going to fight him to the end.
سأقاتله حتى النهاية.
Dad
أبي.
Cutting ties with the Huo family...
اقطعوا علاقتنا ببيت هوو من الآن.
...is a good thing.
وهذا أيضًا أمرٌ جيد.
All I want now is...
أنا الآن لا أريد إلا...
...to live a peaceful life.
أن أعيش حياةً هادئة.